ANDREA VERONICA MENDOZA

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

andimendozait@gmail.com | dreiamendoza.netlify.com

CAREER SUMMARY

Solutions-driven IT professional with experience in developing Web Applications following the highest standards along with the latest trends and technologies. A dedicated team player who can be relied upon to help your company achieve its goals.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

JavaScript | PHP | Python | Java | C#

VueJS | Angular & AngularJS |
ReactJS | Django | NodeJS | J2EE
(w/ Spring & Hibernate) | SuiteCRM
| SugarCRM | Android Native |
Apache Cordova/PhoneGap

Windows, Linux (Ubuntu) | GIT | Atlassian (Bitbucket, JIRA, Confluence), Microsoft TFS | Amazon AWS

PERSONAL SKILLS

- Critical thinker and a quicklearner Persistent and persevering
- Ability to work independently or as part of a team
- Proven leadership skills
- Provide output with minimal supervision
- Willingness to share knowledge as part of a team

REFERENCES

Available on request.

EXPERIENCE

Alliance Software Inc. / Associate Technical Specialist - Development Engr. Jan 2019 - May 2019

- Developed and maintained ground-up web application (franchising system) for one of the country's leading fast-food restaurant chain. Used VueJS, PHP Slim, MySQL.

Alliance Software Inc. / Technical Specialist - Development Engr.

May 2017 - Dec 2018

- Became part of the development team of a US-based startup company for a property management system. Developed modules and did code refactoring as well as one-on-one communication with the client. Used AngularJS, NodeJS, Python-Django (with TDD), MySQL.
- Developed a CRM web application portal for customers of a US-based chemical manufacturing company. Used SugarCRM/SuiteCRM, MSSQL.

Alliance Software Inc. / Bridge Program Participant

April - May 2016

- Attended intensive training with J2EE, Project Management, and basic Nihongo
- Created a Resource Recruitment Web Application using J2EE.

Capstone Project - UC Banilad / Manager - Tech Lead

2016 - 2017

- Managed a team to develop a system of 2 Mobile Applications and a Web Application to track fishermen and their fishing vessels.
- Developed the main tracking module. Used Apache Cordova (PhoneGap), PHP, MySQL.

EDUCATIONAL HISTORY

University of Cebu - Banilad

BS in Information Technology (2017), Magna Cum Laude

2013 - 2017

- Academic Scholar (2013 2017)
- Consistent Top Student & Dean's Lister (2013 2017)
- Mass Media Officer, Assocation of Academic and Science High Scholars (2014 2015)
- Proxor Level 3 Certified Java SDE Developer Exam

Mandaue City Comprehensive Nat'l. High School

Graduated Class of 2013

2009 - 2013

- Top 4 of overall graduating batch